readyrefresh.com 2019-05-26

# Privacy Policy | Nestlé Waters North America

**Nestlé Waters Privacy and Tracking Policy**

Effective August 2012, Last revised January 2017.

Thank you for visiting this Nestlé Waters North America Inc. website. This Privacy Policy describes our information practices with respect to consumer information we collect both online and offline (e.g., when you communicate with us through our various websites, through mobile applications, and at offline programs and events). This Privacy Policy does NOT apply to information collected independently by our affiliate companies, or joint venture partners. 

This Privacy Policy also applies only to our collection and use of information from consumers. It does not apply to our business customers (e.g., retailers, distributors, etc.). It also does not apply to information we might collect and use for employment-related purposes (e.g., resumes, job applications, etc.) or business-to-business related purposes (e.g., media inquiries, investor relations, etc.).

By visiting our site, using our applications, or otherwise providing us with your information, you agree to the practices described in this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy before you submit any personal information on this website. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, you should not use our websites or applications or submit to us any of your information.

**What information about customers do we gather?**

_Contact information_

We may collect your contact information. This might include name and postal address.  We may also collect e-mail address and/or telephone number. We also may collect your account username and password.

_Purchase Information_

If you make a purchase through our website, applications, or our vendors we may collect purchase information.  This includes credit card information and billing address.  It also includes shipping information.

_Other Information_

We may also collect your date of birth, age, or gender.  We may also collect information about your online and browsing behaviors, or your hobbies and interests.  We may also collect information about your household or style preferences.  And we may also collect information about geographic location, such as your zip code, city and state, and mobile location.  

We may also collect or keep track of Internet Protocol (IP) addresses.  An IP address is a number assigned to computers on a network that is used to identify your computer when connected to the Internet. We may also collect information about your computer or device, including your computer's operating system type, your phone's unique device ID, web browser type, and other similar mobile device data. We collect this information, among other things, to: (i) troubleshoot technical concerns; (ii) maintain website safety and security; (iii) restrict access to our website to certain users, and (iv) better understand how our website is utilized.

We, or a third party on our behalf, may also collect log files that record activity when web users access our websites and mobile applications. These logs record, among other things: (i) a user's browser type and operating system; (ii) information about a user's session (such as the URL they came from, the date and time they visited our website, and which pages they have viewed on our site and for how long); and (iii) other similar navigational data. We may also use information captured in log files to gather statistics about our user base and for our internal marketing and demographic studies, so we can constantly improve and customize the online services we provide you. Log files are not associated with any particular user's personal information.

**How do we collect information?**

_When you voluntarily submit information_

We will collect information when you voluntarily provide it to us.  You might do this through one of the online forms available on this website, through our applications, or at offline programs and events.  These are most commonly encountered when:

  * purchasing products or services from this website;
  * registering or signing up for membership on this website;
  * posting comments on message boards and other interactive discussion forms;
  * responding to surveys;
  * participating in sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions;
  * registering for newsletters or other communications from us;  or
  * interacting with us on social media platforms.

We may also collect information you provide us in connection with content that you submit.  This might be content you post on our website or applications, by e-mail, or through text or video message.

_Information automatically collected from you online_

We automatically collect certain technical information from your computer or mobile device when you use our websites or mobile applications. For example, we collect information through the following technologies:

Browser and Flash Cookies

A browser cookie is a small file that websites often store on a user's computer. A Flash cookie is similar to a browser cookie, but is used to store data in conjunction with our web pages that incorporate Adobe Flash applications.  Storage of cookies on your system allows us to personalize or enhance your experience on our website and to make your next visit more convenient and enjoyable. For example, cookies may allow us to remember the content you previously viewed on our website or your log-in information. Cookies may also be used to remember items you have previously placed in your shopping cart when making purchases. We and our third party ad network partners also use cookies to serve interest-based advertisements to you across different websites affiliated with the ad networks, as described in the "Interest-Based Advertising" section below. 

We may link information contained in a cookie to personal information collected from you by other means (e.g., website registration). For more about your choices with respect to cookies, click here.

Clear GIFs

We may use clear GIFs on our website or include them in e-mail messages we send you. Clear GIFs (also known as pixels or web beacons) are small graphic images we include on a web page or in an e-mail message that allow us to determine how users interact with the web page or e-mail. Clear GIFs may be used to share information between us and our advertising partners, or to allow us, or our advertising partners, to communicate with cookies stored on your device. We may also use cookies, clear GIFs, and other tools to collect information about your interactions with third party websites. Clear GIFs may be used to serve interest-based advertisements to you across different websites affiliated with advertising networks, as described in the "Interest-Based Advertising" section below. 

The information collected via clear GIFs may also include some of the information described in the "Other information" section above, as well as information about how a user responds to an e-mail campaign (such as, the time the e-mail is opened, where does the user link to from the e-mail, etc.). We use information collected this way for a variety of purposes, including but not limited to site traffic reporting, unique visitor counts, promotions and marketing involving our advertising partners, advertising and e-mail auditing and reporting, and content personalization.

_From third parties or other sources_

We may also obtain information about you from other sources. For example, we may hire a third party data aggregator to provide us additional information about our existing consumers (this is known as "data appending"). We may also receive information from third parties, such as co-sponsors who we may occasionally partner with to run special contests or other promotions.  We may also collect or obtain information from social media platforms. We may also collect information through the use of third party web analytics services (such as Google Analytics) such as number of visits to a particular page, or the amount of time spent on a web site.  We may also receive information about consumers when we acquire part or all of other companies.

We may also get information from other consumers. For example, we may offer e-cards or tell-a-friend features. 

_Combining Information_

We may combine information we get from one source with other information we may have about you. This might include combining information you submit online with information you submit offline, or information that you submit by e-mail with information that you submit through our websites. Or we may combine information we received from a third party with information you submit to us.

**How do we use the information we collect?**

_For the purpose collected_

Information collected is used for the purpose for which the information was collected, as otherwise identified to you, or as described in this Privacy Policy. For example, if you make an online purchase, we will use your credit card information to fulfill and process your purchases.  Also, if you register or open an account on this website, the information you provide may be used to maintain your account, to provide you access to certain features of our website, or offer you the benefits and privileges that typically come along with registration. This may include purchasing products and/or services.  It may also include access to and use of exclusive or personalized content or activities (such as message boards), participation in special events and promotions (contests, sweepstakes, coupons, etc.).  As part of this, we may use your information to determine your eligibility, notify you whether you are a winner, and/or fulfill and deliver prizes.  

_To respond to inquiries_

Similarly, we may use your information to respond to your requests or inquiries, For example, if you contact us via an online contact form, your information may be used to respond to your inquiry or comment.

_To send communications and for marketing purposes  _

We may use your information to provide you with marketing or other information about our products and services through any communications medium, including but not limited to (i) through e-mail, (ii) on our website and mobile applications, (iii) on third party websites and mobile applications, and (iv) by text message.  We will also use your information to send you transactional communications about your account or relationship with us.

From time to time, we may be approached by reputable third party companies and organizations that provide products or services that we believe may be of interest to you. To help you find these useful products or services, we may use your personal information to send out notices on their behalf.

We may also use your personal and/or demographic information for our internal marketing and demographic studies, so we can constantly improve, personalize, and customize the products and services we provide you and to better meet your needs. This may include occasionally combining, updating, or otherwise enhancing the personal information collected through this website with data we receive from outside records or third parties. We may also use your information to improve our websites and applications.

_For other legitimate business purposes_

We may also use your information for other general business purposes, such as to maintain the day-to-day operation and security of our websites and applications and to conduct internal marketing and demographic studies.

We may also use your information as permitted by law or in the manner communicated to you.

**Who is collecting your information and is it shared with anyone?**

The information that you disclose on this website is collected by Nestlé Waters North America Inc. or by a third party acting on our behalf; and is used in accordance with the practices set forth above and for other reasons we may describe to you.  We may also permit third parties to collect information about your use of the website for their own purposes (e.g., through the use of cookies, clear GIFs, and similar tools). These third parties' use of such tools is not in our control, and they may use or share the information they collect according to their own privacy policies. The following provides more specific information about how and to whom we may disclose your information.

_Affiliated Companies_

We may share your personal information with our subsidiary, parent and affiliate companies in which Nestlé S.A. has control through either direct or indirect ownership (collectively "Nestlé Group").

_Agents and Contractors_

We may use third party agents or contractors to provide support for our internal operations. We also may use third party agents or contractors to assist us in marketing our products and services, including but not limited through a cooperative marketing program.  These third parties may collect information on our behalf. We may also share information with them.   We might use third parties for fulfilling orders, delivering packages, or sending postal mail, e-mail, or text messages on our behalf.  We might also use third parties to remove repetitive information from customer lists or analyze data.  They might also provide marketing assistance, process credit card payment or provide customer service. 

_Partners and Joint Promotions_

From time to time, we may run a joint or co-sponsored program or promotion with another company, organization, affiliate or other reputable third party, or group of third parties; and, as part of this program or promotion, collect and process personal information.  We may share your personal information with any such third party and we may provide a separate link to that company's website. If you do not want your information to be collected by or shared with any such third party, you can choose not to participate in these programs or promotions at the time the information is collected/requested. Those third parties may use your information as described in any privacy policy associated with the program or promotion, which may include their privacy policies.  We encourage you to carefully review any such privacy policy and other conditions of use. We may share your information if you win a sweepstakes or contest as part of a winner's list. We may also publish this winner's list publicly.

_Advertising Partners_

We may share your information with advertising partners so that they can better understand your behaviors and browsing activities and so that we and our advertising partners can serve content relevant to you. Our advertising partners may use cookies, clear GIFs, and other tools to collect information over time about your interaction with our websites and unaffiliated websites. Our advertising partners may append information collected by these tools to information obtained from other sources. This Privacy Policy does not address or govern how advertising partners may collect, use, and share information.   
Similarly, to better understand your behaviors and browsing activities and to serve content relevant to you, we may use cookies, clear GIFs, and other tools to collect information about your interaction with third party websites. Any information collected from a third party website or third party tool is governed by that entity's privacy policy and is not subject to this Privacy Policy. 

Please see the "Interest Based Advertising" section of this Privacy Policy to learn more about how third parties may use tools and information on our behalf or for their own purposes.

_Legal and Business Transfers_

We may also disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law, or if in our good faith judgment, such action is reasonably necessary to comply with legal processes, to respond to any claims, or to protect the safety or rights of Nestlé Waters North America Inc., its customers, or the public.

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy stores or assets. In such transactions, personal information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the event of a merger or acquisition of all or part of Nestlé Waters North America Inc. or Nestlé Group by another company, or in the event that Nestlé Waters North America Inc. or Nestlé Group were to sell or dispose of all or a part of the Nestlé Group business, the acquirer would have access to the information maintained by that Nestlé Group business, which could include personal information, subject to applicable law. Similarly, personal information may be transferred as part of a corporate reorganization, insolvency proceeding, or other similar event, if permitted by and done in accordance with applicable law.

**What safeguards do we use to protect your personal information?**

Nestlé Waters North America Inc. takes commercially reasonable effects to protect the confidentiality and security of the personal information collected from our website visitors. These efforts may include, but are not necessarily limited to: (i) storing your personal information in secure operating environments; (ii) using industry standard methods to protect the security of certain sensitive personal information (such as credit card information) during transmission to our websites; and (iii) authenticating registered website users before they can access the personal information we maintain about them.

If you use this site to access your online account, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account and password and for restricting access to your computer, and you agree to accept responsibility for all activities that occur under your account or password.

**What choices do I have?**

The following outlines the choices you have with respect to the collection and use of your personal information by Nestlé Waters North America Inc.

  * You can choose not to voluntarily share information with us. However, if you choose this option, you will be limited in the activities and features we can provide you.
  * You can opt out of marketing e-mails by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in any marketing e-mail you receive from us.  If you are a Ready Refresh by Nestlé customer or otherwise have an online account with us and opt out of marketing e-mails, we will still send you transactional e-mails about your account. These include messages about your orders or your account. They also include other e-mails about your relationship with us.

  * You can always review or update any personal information that we may have collected about you for our general website registration by visiting the appropriate update profile sections of the website.

In addition, please note that if you participated in a promotion or program that involved a third party company and, as part of that promotion, you agreed to receive future communications directly from that third party, you will need to contact the third party (not Nestlé Waters North America Inc.) directly to opt out from such communications. This process may be outlined in the third party's privacy policy..

**Children**

This website is a general audience website. We do not sell products for purchase by children or knowingly collect personal information from any person under the age of 13. Children under the age of 13 should always get their parent's or guardian's consent before providing information to anyone via the Internet. If you are under the age of 13, you should not register or provide any information on our Web site. We do not sell products for purchase by children. If you are under 18, you may use this site only with involvement of a parent or guardian.

**Links to Other Websites**

Our websites and applications may provide links to, or features from, other third party sites (such as independent e-commerce sites and third party social networks). If you link to or use such third party sites or features, you do so at your own risk. We do not control and are not responsible for the content or practices of any third party site, application, or feature.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

If you are a California resident, you may have the right to request and receive certain information about our disclosure of your personal information to third parties for their own marketing use, and your choices with respect to such disclosures. If you wish to learn more about our compliance with this requirement, you may contact Consumer Affairs.

**How to contact us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us at:

Nestlé Waters North America Inc.

900 Long Ridge Road, Building 2

Stamford, Connecticut 06902

**Changes to the policy**

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy. Any changes will be posted in this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy whenever you come back to this website to make sure you are aware of any changes and how your information may be used. If we make any revisions that materially change the ways in which we use or share the information previously collected from you, we will give you the opportunity to consent to such changes before applying them to that information. Otherwise, your continued use of this website signifies your acceptance of these changes.

**Interest-Based Advertising**

We use certain online technologies, such as cookies and clear GIFs, to collect information about you over time and across different websites when you use this website or service, as described in the "How do we collect information" section of this Privacy Policy.  We also allow third parties to collect information this way.  We use these technologies to serve you with interest-based advertising and to better understand your behaviors and browsing activities.  We partner with third party ad networks to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partners use tools such as cookies and clear GIFs to collect information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you advertising based upon your interests on both our and third party websites and mobile applications.  Our third party partners may use or share information collected by us, information they collect from our websites, or information they collect from cookies on your device for their own purposes, including serving you with interest-based advertising. Such use and sharing is governed by the third party partners' privacy policies, not this Privacy Policy. For more information, please see the "Advertising Partners" section of this Privacy Policy.  

If you wish to not receive interest-based ads from some of our ad network partners, you may opt out by [clicking here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). Please note that this may not opt you out of interest-based ads from all of our ad network partners. It also does not opt you out of being served non-interest-based advertising from our ad network partners.  It also does not opt you out of receiving interest-based advertising from us, our affiliated companies, partners, and joint promoters as described in the "Who is collecting your information and is it shared with anyone" section of this Privacy Policy. 

_Cookies_

You can always disable cookies or set your browser to alert you when cookies are being sent to your computer. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. However, if you do so, you may not be able to register on our website or use other features that require registration or the collection of information.

Please note that Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the way in which Flash cookies capture and store data. Your browser's cookie management tools will not remove flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here:

<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>

_Do Not Track_

**Some browsers have a feature that lets you communicate a "Do Not Track" signal to the websites your visit.   There is no standard response to this feature, so note that our websites may not recognize Do Not Track headers or signals from some or all browsers.**  If you block or delete cookies, not all of the automatic information collection that we have described in this Privacy Policy will stop.

Options you select may be browser and device specific.

**You can control some of the ways that you interact with us on your mobile devices.** For example, you can decline to transmit GPS data to mobile applications or to receive push notifications on your phone.
